(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-05T20:53:20.220348",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あわてんぼうのサンタクロース
Scatterbrained Santa Claus
クリスマスまえにやってきた
He arrived before Christmas day!
いそいでリンリンリン
Hurry, ring ring ring!
ならしてくれよかねを
Please ring a bell for us!
リンリンリン リンリンリン リンリンリン
Ring ring ring, ring ring ring...
あわてんぼうのサンタクロース
Scatterbrained Santa Claus
えんとつのぞいておっこちた
He peeked in the chimney and fell down!
あいたたどんどんどん
Ouch, bang bang bang!
まっくろくけのおかお
His face was smudged with soot!
どんどんどん どんどんどん どんどんどん
Bang bang bang, bang bang bang...
あわてんぼうのサンタクロース
Scatterbrained Santa Claus
しかたがないからおどったよ
There was nothing he could do but dance!
たのしくちゃちゃちゃ
It's so fun, cha cha cha!
みんなも踊ろよ、僕と
Everyone dance with me!
チャチャチャ チャチャチャ チャチャチャ
Cha-cha-cha...
あわてんぼうのサンタクロース
Hasty Santa Claus,
もう一度来るよと帰っていく
He says he'll come again and goes back.
さようなら シャラランラン
Goodbye, shara ran ran!
タンブリン鳴らして消えた
He disappeared playing the tambourine.
シャラランラン シャラランラン シャラランラン
Shara ran ran...
あわてんぼうのサンタクロース
Hasty Santa Claus,
ゆかいなひげのおじさん
A merry bearded old man.
リンリンリン チャチャチャ ドンドンどん シャラランラン
Rin-rin-rin, cha-cha-cha, don-don-don, shara ran ran!
わすれちゃだめだよおもちゃ
Don't forget the toys!
リンリンリン チャチャチャ ドンシャララン
Rin-rin-rin, cha-cha-cha, don shara ran!
はい、どーも！
Hi, everyone!
あわてんぼうのサンタクロース！……って、え、
Hasty Santa Claus... wait, no!
え、後ろの鹿してたの！？団長！後ろが寝るんですー！
Wait, was that Dain-san back there, Dancho?! He's sleeping!
みんな、今日は何の日か知ってますか？
Does everyone know what day today is?
そうだよ、めちゃめちゃ大切な日だよねー！
That's right, it's a super important day!
そう、みなさん知ってのとおりクリスマス・イブだよ、わーい！
Yes, as you all know, it's Christmas Eve! Yay!
え、いまね、こう画面上で見てるみんなもクリスマスライブの様子、いっぱいこうやってスクリーンショットして、SNSで投稿してください、よろしくお願いします！
If you're watching on screen, please take lots of screenshots and post them on SNS!
これね、ハッシュタグは、こちらのとなっております、みんないっぱいスクリーンショットちょうだいね！
The hashtag is right here, everyone please send me lots of screenshots!
そして、あの、今回クリスマスライブということでステージもクリスマス仕様となっております！うわあ、すごい！あの、いつもね、あの、団長こう、前に、あの、おうきゅうのね、感じ作ってもらったんですけど、その、あの、街並みが、え、なんか、パワーアップして、クリスマス仕様となってます！いやあ、すごいですね、煙突とかもね、そうがだいすね、わあっとなってますけれど、
And since it's a Christmas live stream, the stage is also Christmas-themed! Wow, amazing! Usually Dancho has a palace setup in front, but that townscape has powered up into a Christmas version! It's amazing, even the chimneys are decked out!
いやあ、他にもね、ちょっといろいろと見て、見たいなあ、見れるのかなあ？
Man, I want to look around at other things too. Can I see them?
あ！プレゼント！やっぱクリスマスといったらプレゼントですよねー！いや、いっぱいありがとうございます！ここではだいんさんからの、愛かな？ありがとうございます！
Ah, presents! Speaking of Christmas, it's presents! Thank you so much! Is this love from Dain-san? Thank you!
そして、やっぱ他にもね、クリスマスといったら、ずるるるる、上のこちらの、はい！リースもあります！なんかね、だんちょく、クリスマスといったらやっぱリースかなって思ったんですけど、まあ、でも、ここらへんね、ちょっと気づいた方もいると思うんですけど、いやあ、
And of course, up here, yes! There's a wreath too! I thought a wreath is a must for Christmas, but um, I think some of you might have noticed...
あと何だろな、街並みとかね、プレゼント、リースでサンタさんでしょ？あ！一番大事ですね、こちら！そう、クリスマス・ツリー！
What else? Townscapes, presents, wreaths, Santa... Ah, the most important one! The Christmas tree!
やっぱね、クリスマスツリーはクリスマスに欠かせませんけど、いや、どうやってライトアップする？やっぱさ、このなんだろ、ね、なんか、こう、木が装飾しててもやっぱキラキラ光んないとクリスマスじゃない！どうしようどうしようどうしよう！ええ、どうしようかなあ、悩む…！
A Christmas tree is essential, but how do we light it up? Even if it's decorated, if it doesn't sparkle, it's not Christmas! What should I do, I'm worried...!
待って！うわっ、あ！だいんさん！あ、なんか動いてる！きゃあ！えっ、なんかこんなに動けたっけ、だいんさん！よかったね、あみおみんして…！
Wait! Woah, ah, Dain-san! You're moving?! Kyaa! Eh, could Dain-san move this much? I'm so glad you could do the Ami-Omin...
あ、さっきね、そう、だいんさん、あの、大変だった？うんうん、でも引いてくれてありがとう！いや、かっこいいよ、大柄のつのものに似合ってます！かわいい！いやあ、クリスマス楽しんでますね！
Ah, earlier, was it tough, Dain-san? Yeah, but thanks for pulling! You look cool, it suits those big antlers! Cute! You're really enjoying Christmas!
ということでね、本日の、ま、クリスマスライブ、まだ成功したわけではありません！そう、最後まで成功するか分からない！なんと、だいんさんの力が必要です！だいんさんの応援、そして頑張りも、あのクリスマスライブの成功の、あの、鍵になっておりますので、ぜひぜひ応援よろしくお願いします！
So today's Christmas live stream hasn't succeeded yet! We don't know if it'll succeed until the very end! We need Dain-san's power! Your support and hard work are the key to making this a success, so please support us!
ではクリスマス準備をしつつ、ライブを楽しんでいきましょう！いやあ、でもクリスマスね、一人で、まあ、だいんさんもいるけど、一人でなんか…
Now, while preparing for Christmas, let's enjoy the live stream! But Christmas, alone... well, Dain-san is here too, but alone...
あのさ、ちょっと寂しいので
Since it's a bit lonely,
お友達も呼んでます！
I've invited my friends too!
お友達とクリスマスライブ、歌って踊るぞー！
Let's sing and dance with my friends at our Christmas live!
わあーい！
Yay!
楽しみだぞー！
I'm so excited!
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は
Ah, the town is like a whipped cake,
好き！雪！本気Magic
Love! Snow! Really Magic!
空がくれるコンフェッティは
The confetti given by the sky
冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ Woo
is the angel's wings celebrating the winter festival, Woo!
白銀の国へ 出かけるのさ Go Go Go
Let's head out to the silver land, Go Go Go!
雪の汽車が 街を駆け Choo Choo Choo
The snow train dashes through the town, Choo Choo Choo!
絵本みたいな景色を 君に見せてあげるから
Because I'll show you a scenery like a picture book,
願い込めて呪文 さあ （さあ） 唱えて （はいっ）
Make a wish and chant the spell, Now (Now) Chant it (1, 2, 3!)
abcd ドド シシ ララ シシ マジカル ミラクルクル ポップ
A-B-C-D do-do-shi-shi-ra-ra-shi-shi Magical Miracle-cle-cle Pop!
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は
Ah, the town is like a whipped cake,
好き！雪！本気Magic
Love! Snow! Really Magic!
空がくれるコンフェッティは
The confetti given by the sky
冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ
is the angel's wings celebrating the winter festival,
Light Upした オーロラ色の街は
The lit-up aurora-colored town is
好き！雪！本気Magic
Love! Snow! Really Magic!
子どもでいられたら Dream Land
If I could remain a child, Dream Land!
ツンと冷たい 季節が好き Love Love Love
The sharp, cold season is what I love, Love Love Love!
アイスも魔法も とけないように ヒュー ヒュー ヒュー
So that ice and magic won't melt away, Woo-hoo-hoo!
ずっとこのままじゃ ダメなの？ やっぱり ドキドキしたいな
Is it no good staying like this forever? Still, I want my heart to go doki-doki!
未来 求め 呪文 今 （なう） と唱えて （はいっ）
Seeking the future, chant the spell now (Now) Chant it (1, 2, 3!)
1 2 3 4 水金地火木 マジカル ミラクルクル ポップ
1, 2, 3, 4, Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars, Jupiter! Magical Miracle-cle-cle Pop!
Ah ホップした ウサギのような 気分 好き！雪！本気Magic
Ah, a rabbit-like hopping mood, Love! Snow! Really Magic!
大地がくれる 元気得たら 思い通り 明日を生きていけるよ
If I get the energy given by the earth, I can live tomorrow just as I want!
まぶしい白に 染まるハート 君に 好き！雪！本気Magic
A heart dyed in dazzling white, to you, Love! Snow! Really Magic!
大人のふり なんて いいじゃん
Acting like an adult is totally fine!
今日の寒さも 忘れるように
So that we can forget today's cold as well,
悩みだって悩みだって 凍らせて 消せる魔力よ （もっかい！）
Let's freeze even worries, even worries, And make them vanish with magical power! (Once more!)
abcd ドド シシ ララ シシ マジカル ミラクルクル ポップ
A-B-C-D do-do-shi-shi-ra-ra-shi-shi Magical Miracle-cle-cle Pop!
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は
Ah, the town is like a whipped cake,
好き！雪！本気Magic
Love! Snow! Really Magic!
空がくれるコンフェッティは
The confetti given by the sky
冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ
is the angel's wings celebrating the winter festival,
Light Upした オーロラ色の街は
The lit-up aurora-colored town is
好き！雪！本気Magic
Love! Snow! Really Magic!
子どもでいられたら Dream Land
If I could remain a child, Dream Land!
いいじゃん
That's fine!
はじめてのキスは涙の味がした
The first kiss tasted like tears.
まるでドラマみたいな恋
It was like the love in dramas.
見計らったように発車のベルが鳴った
As if waiting for the right moment, the departure bell rang.
冷たい冬の風が頬をかすめる
A winter wind brushes my cheek.
吐いた息で両手をこすった
So I blew on my hands and rubbed them together.
街はイルミネーション 魔法をかけたみたい 裸の街路樹キラキラ
The city is lighted by an illumination, as if magically casted, and made the naked trees sparkle.
どうしても言えなかった この気持ち押さえつけた
I just couldn't say it, my feelings I kept inside.
はじめてのキスは涙の味がした
The first kiss tasted like tears.
まるでドラマみたいな恋
It was like a romance in a drama.
見計らったように発車のベルが鳴った
As if on cue, the departure bell rang.
冷たい冬の風が頬をかすめる
The cold winter wind brushes my cheek.
吐いた息で両手をこすった
I breathed on my hands and rubbed them together.
街はイルミネーション 魔法をかけたみたい
The city's illuminations look like magic.
裸の街路樹キラキラ
Bare roadside trees glittering.
どうしても言えなかった
I just couldn't say it.
この気持ち 押さえつけた
I kept these feelings suppressed.
前から決めていた事だから
Because I decided this beforehand.
これでいいの 振り向かないから
This is fine, since I won't look back.
ありがとう サヨナラ
Thank you, goodbye.
切ない片思い
A bittersweet unrequited love.
足を止めれば思い出してしまうから
If I stop, I'll only remember it all.
ありがとう サヨナラ
Thank you, goodbye.
泣いたりしないから
Because I won't cry.
そう思った途端にふわり 舞い降りてくる雪
The moment I thought that, softly, snow fluttered down.
触れたら溶けてきえた
When touched, it melted and vanished.
駅へと続く大通り 寄り添っている二人 楽しそう
The street to the station, a couple close by looking happy.
「ほら見て初雪！」
"Look, first snow!"
キミとあんな風になりたくて 初めて作った手編みのマフラー
I wanted to be like that with you, my first hand-knitted muffler.
どうしたら渡せたんだろう
How could I have given it to you?
意気地なし 怖かっただけ
I was just a coward, too scared.
思い出になるならこのままで構わないって
If it's just a memory, I'm fine leaving it as is.
それは本当なの？
Is that really true?
ありがとう サヨナラ
Thank you, goodbye.
いつかこんな時が来てしまうこと 分かってたはずだわ
I knew a time like this would come eventually.
なのに
Yet...
ありがとう サヨナラ
Thank you, goodbye.
体が震えてる
My body is trembling.
もうすぐ列車が来るのに
Even though the train will arrive any minute.
それはいまになって 私を苦しめる
Now that's only tormenting me.
つながりたい どれほど願っただろう
How much I wished to be connected.
この手は空っぽ
This hand is empty.
ねぇ サヨナラってこういうこと？
Hey, is this what a goodbye feels like?
行かなくちゃ そんなのわかってる
I have to go, I know that.
キミが優しい事も知ってる
And I know you're kind, too.
だから 「……この手を離してよ」
So... "Let go of this hand."
出会えてよかった
I'm glad we met.
キミが好き
I love you.
ありがとう サヨナラ
Thank you, goodbye.
一言が言えない
I can't say a single word.
今だけでいい 私に勇気を
Just for now, give me the courage.
「あのね──」 言いかけた唇
The lips that were about to say "You know..."
キミとの距離は0
The distance to you is zero.
……今だけは泣いていいよね
……It's okay to cry just for now, right?
もう言葉はいらない
I don't need any more words.
お願いぎゅっとしていて
Please hold me tight.
来年の今頃には
By this time next year,
どんな私が居て どんなキミが居るのかな
I wonder what kind of me and you will be here.
行かなくちゃ そんなのわかってる
I have to go, I know that.
キミが優しい事も知ってる
And I know you're kind, too.
だから この手を離してよ
So... let go of this hand.
出会えてよかった
I'm glad we met.
キミが好き
I love you.
ありがとう サヨナラ
Thank you, goodbye.
一言が言えない
I can't say a single word.
今だけでいい 私に勇気を
Just for now, give me the courage.
「あのね──」 言いかけた唇
The lips that were about to say "You know..."
キミとの距離は0
The distance to you is zero.
……今だけは泣いていいよね
……It's okay to cry just for now, right?
もう言葉はいらない
I don't need any more words.
お願いぎゅっとしていて
Please hold me tight.
来年の今頃には
By this time next year,
どんな私が居て
I wonder what kind of me will be here,
どんなキミが居るのかな
what kind of you will be here.
先輩！
Senpai!
おめでとうございまーす！
Happy birthday!
なんか出たよ！
Something popped out!
よいしょ、よいしょ
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
今回はクリスマス会に来ていただきありがとうございます！
Thank you all for coming to our Christmas party today!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
いや、あの二人間は、え、もしかしてなんですけど
Wait, those two... um, could it be...
あの3Dね、あの、最近なったじゃないですか
With the 3D models, you know, you guys just got them recently, right?
そっから、え、先輩へのゲストとかってあったり？
Since then, um, did you have guests or anything for Senpai?
え、実は、じつは
Um, actually, actually...
初めて！
For the first time!
初めてです！
It's the first time!
二人が元気に動いてる姿こんな間近に見れて
Seeing the two of you moving around so energetically up close...
なんか動きがアレ？
Wait, why are your movements so weird?
だってもう！イェーイ！イェーイ！
Because, well— Yay! Yay! Yay!
ちょっと、なんかハイテンションじゃあ、てる、ですけど
Wait, you guys are super high-tension right now, but...
いやでもね、あの二人を呼んだ理由、ちゃんとあります！
Yeah, but you know, there's a proper reason why I invited these two!
おっ？
Oh?
え、何ですか？
What is it?
動きが変
Your movements are weird!
いや、確かに、なんか、確かに！あの、いやなんか、
Well, true, I mean, true! Um, well,
登場したときにね、なんか二人ちょっと動き似てて
when you guys appeared, your movements were kind of similar,
団長ね、ちょっと、あの、ありがとうございます！嬉しい、嬉しいね！嬉しい！
and Leader, um... Thank you so much! I'm so happy, so happy! Yay!
だけど、そうではなく！うん！
But that's not it! Yeah!
あの、ま、今日ね、歌った曲、歌ったことあるよね？
Um, well, today the song we sang... you've sung it before, right?
そうなんです！
That's right!
カバーしたことあるね！是非、あのリリカちゃんの歌ってみたも聞いてください！
We've covered it before! Everyone, please check out Lirica-chan's cover too!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ぜひぜひ！
Please do!
でも今回のほうがめちゃめちゃめっっちゃいい感じなんですね、そっちは、
But this time's version is so, so, so good, so that one...
イェーイ！イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
そしてね、やっぱかなたんわね、
And you know, as expected, Kanatan is...
はい！
Yes!
もう団長デジロスの中で一番絡んでる、もう娘！
She's practically my daughter, interacting with me the most in my circle!
がんばれ！のえるママ！たのしーちゅう！
Do your best! Mama Noel! Having fun!
やばね、呼ばなきゃと思って、呼ぼうと思いました！
I thought, "Oh no, I gotta invite her," so I decided to!
よかったぁ！で、呼べばよかった、ワブに…わぶれない！
I'm so glad! And I'm so glad I invited you... wait, I'm stumbling!
いや嬉しい！ありがとね、ほんと歌えたも来てくれて。ありがとうございます！
I'm so happy! Thank you so much for coming to sing with us. Thank you!
ちなみに、お二人はクリスマスの思い出とかってありますか？
By the way, do you two have any Christmas memories?
はい！おっ！あります！
Yes! Oh! I do!
なんでしょう？
What is it?
やっぱりクリスマスといえば、ケーキじゃないですか？
Well, when you think of Christmas, you think of cake, right?
だから、クリスマスが終わった翌日に安くなったケーキをいっぱい食べることです！
So, my memory is eating lots of discounted cake the day after Christmas!
あー素敵だ！ラッキーいい思い出！
Ah, that's wonderful! What a lucky, great memory!
ま、でもね、やっぱ味は変わんないしね！
Well, but the taste doesn't change, after all!
そう、そう！でも安くなったやる、やったね！おいしさは２倍！
That's right! But getting them cheaper is awesome! The deliciousness is doubled!
リリカちゃんらしさ限界を感じますけれど、え、かなでちゃんは何ですか？
I feel Lirica's unique limit right there, but Kanade-chan, what about you?
あ、かなでも思い出あります！あるんだ、いいね！なんだ？
Ah, Kanade has a memory too! Oh you do, nice! What is it?
きっとよいこのみんなはちょっとだけお耳を閉じててね、もう言わないから！
All you good children out there, cover your ears for just a second, I won't say it anymore!
え、ちょっとクリスマスのときに、あの幼稚園にいた時のお話なんですけど、幼稚園のところで、あの来た、あのサンタのコスプレをしたおっさん…おっさん？おっさん…
Um, so during Christmas, when I was in kindergarten, it's a story about when an old man dressed up as Santa came to the kindergarten... An old man? An old man...
おっさん？サンタさんでしょ、それ！
An old man? That's Santa Claus!
白いカツラのしたにカツラって言わないで！
Underneath his white wig— Don't call it a wig!
言ってたことが甘いんです！
What he said was so naive!
なんか現実を、違うよね。染めは忘れちゃった…染めは忘れちゃったから、それは嘘だったんじゃない？おしゃれね！おしゃれだじゃお前！
It's different from reality, right? The dye got forgotten... Since the dye got forgotten, wasn't that a lie? So fashionable! You're just being fashionable!
やっぱ釣られたくなっちゃう、サンタさん本ってことで！
You end up wanting to get hooked, treating it like the real Santa!
ということで、お二人も本当いい思い出をありがとうございます！
With that said, thank you both so much for sharing your great memories!
いいよ！はい！やったね！
You're welcome! Yes! Yay!
いやでもこれからもね、まだまだ、あのクリスマスライブを続けていくので、ちょっとお二人にはちょっとね、ここで、おっ？な、になっちゃうんですが！
And you know, since we'll continue our Christmas live from here on, I'd like to ask you two to... oh? What's going to happen?
寂しい！やだ、ずっといたい！本当に、そう、本当に。ね、かなでちゃんもさりげなくいそうですが、で、まだちょっと残っててね、あのちょっと団長 ちょっとお二人にちょっとお願いがあります！
I'm sad! No, I want to stay forever! Really, really. You know, Kanade-chan is casually sticking around too, but please stay a bit longer... Leader, I have a request for you two!
おっ？何でしょう？あの、後ろの、こちら、見えますか？
Oh? What is it? Um, the thing in the back here, can you see it?
このでっかい、でっかい、この届かないじゃん、ジャンプしても届かないよ！
This huge, huge thing— we can't reach it! Even if we jump, we can't reach it!
どれだけいでしょ、このクリスマスツリーに飾り付けをお願いしてもいいですか？
Would you mind decorating this Christmas tree for us?
もちろん！やったー！一緒に飾り付けしましょう！
Of course! Yay! Let's decorate it together!
はい！いくぞ！いくぞ！
Yes! Let's go! Let's go!
わあ！やった！やった！
Wow! Yay! Yay!
飾り付けするぞー！おおー！
Let's decorate! Woohoo!
じゃあまずはかなでちゃんから！
First up is Kanade-chan!
がんばる！どこにいよっかな？かなでちゃん！
I'll do my best! Where should I put it? Kanade-chan!
はい！うん！じゃあもういく？ナギ長ー！ナギ長ちゃんがって！
Yes! Yup! Then shall we go? Nagichou! Nagichou-chan is putting it!
おっ！うわー！やった！いいよ！いいよ！
Oh! Wow! Yay! Good job! Good job!
すごーい！うわーい！
Amazing! Yay!
あいつぎつける？
Who's next to attach one?
はい！レリカつけます！どこにつけるんだ？
Yes! Lirica will attach one! Where should I put it?
どうしようかな？かわいい。あでもここらへんとか良さそうかも。
What should I do? So cute. Oh, but around here looks good.
じゃあ華麗に、これすー。ボーリングみたいだったね！
Then, gracefully... like this. That looked like bowling!
うつすてき！やったー！ありがとう！
How lovely! Yay! Thank you!
完璧、完璧！ありがとう、お二人とも！やったー！
Perfect, perfect! Thank you both! Yay!
ありがとうございます！ありがとう！引き続きがんばってくださいね！
Thank you very much! Thank you! Please keep doing your best!
がんばる！がんばるぞー！イェーイ！
I'll do my best! Let's do our best! Yay!
全身小悪魔精神性
Total little devil mentality,
柑橘香水系フローラル短命を
citrus perfume-style floral, short-lived...
恋まで発展しちゃうぞ
Development all the way to romance!
わっ！
Whoa!
大胆 大胆 アタシってハッピー
Bold, bold, I'm so happy!
お招き 本気の じゅなじゅなボーイ
Inviting you, my serious, pure-pure boy!
豪快 豪快 悩殺スマイル
Grand, grand, heart-killing smile!
慌ててきゅんきゅん ハニーハニーYeah!
Flustered, thumping, honey-honey Yeah!
ホロホロで ほれほれで バイタル不安定ね
Crumbling, swooning, our vitality is unstable, huh?
軽口叩いて 本気の じゅなじゅなボーイ
Talking big, you serious, pure-pure boy!
ホロホロで ほれほれで バイタル不安定ね
Crumbling, swooning, our vitality is unstable, huh?
慌ててきゅんきゅん ハニーハニーYeah!
Flustered, thumping, honey-honey Yeah!
全身小悪魔 精神性 あなたを完全掌握です
Total little devil, mental state: you're completely under my control.
盲目ハッピーアンラッキー 真面目な恋とか気にしちゃめ
Blindly happy, unlucky. Don't worry about serious romance!
全身小悪魔 精神性 フローラル短潔香水デイ
Total little devil, mental state, floral concise perfume day.
よそみやばってん 恋まで発展しちゃうぞわっ！
Looking away is forbidden, development all the way to romance, whoa!
イジワルしちゃうぞしちゃうぞ
I'll tease you, I'll tease you!
惚れちゃいな
Fall for me!
ドキドキ肝心なドライ
A thrilling, crucial dry spell!
イジワルしちゃうぞしちゃうぞ
I'll tease you, I'll tease you!
可愛くね
Being cute?
付き合ってとかダメダメ独占じゃん
Saying "let's go out" is a no-no, isn't that monopolizing?
イタズラァニャ！イタズラァニャ！イタズラァニャ！怒らないでね
Mischief-nya! Mischief-nya! Mischief-nya! Don't get mad!
イタズラァニャ！イタズラァニャ！イタズラァニャ！アタシだけの愛
Mischief-nya! Mischief-nya! Mischief-nya! Only my love!
毎晩毎晩 見るくて反省
Every single night, looking back and reflecting.
からめのむちむち 気分気分が
Spicy, plump, my mood, my mood is...
大変大変 肌ケアエイジング
Terribly hard, skin care, aging...
夜更かしNG ピュアピュアC
Staying up late is NG, pure-pure C!
ホロホロで 転がして たまにはほっといて
Crumbling, rolling, leave me alone sometimes.
欲しがりさん むちむち 気分気分が
Greedy one, plump, my mood, my mood is...
ホロホロで 転がして たまにはほっといて
Crumbling, rolling, leave me alone sometimes.
嘘から 3度目のスルー
From lies, the third time's a pass.
イジワルしちゃうぞしちゃうぞ 冷めちゃいや
I'll tease you, I'll tease you, don't let the mood die!
ほら眼中ないなんてWhy?
Look, how can you not even notice me, Why?
イジワルしちゃうぞしちゃうぞ 変えちゃいや
I'll tease you, I'll tease you, don't change your mind!
でも範疇ダイヤイヤ反抗タイム
But scope-wise, diamond-no-no rebellion time!
イタズラァニャ！イタズラァニャ！イタズラァニャ！怒らないでね
Mischief-nya! Mischief-nya! Mischief-nya! Don't get mad!
イタズラァニャ！イタズラァニャ！イタズラァニャ！アタシだけの愛
Mischief-nya! Mischief-nya! Mischief-nya! Only my love!
ちょっちょ 可愛くない？
Hey, hey, isn't it cute?
ちょっちょ 答えてよ
Hey, hey, answer me!
ちょっちょ 寂しいな
Hey, hey, I'm lonely!
ちょっちょ わからずや
Hey, hey, you stubborn blockhead!
ちょっちょ 可愛くない？
Hey, hey, isn't it cute?
ちょっちょ 答えてよ
Hey, hey, answer me!
ちょっちょ 寂しいな
Hey, hey, I'm lonely!
それじゃあ私もイタズラだ！
Then I'll play tricks on you too!
全身小悪魔 精神性 あなたを完全掌握です
Total little devil, mental state: you're completely under my control.
盲目ハッピーアンラッキー 真面目な恋とか気にしちゃめ
Blindly happy, unlucky. Don't worry about serious romance!
全身小悪魔 精神性 フローラル短潔香水デイ
Total little devil, mental state, floral concise perfume day.
よそみやばってん 恋まで発展しちゃうぞわっ！
Looking away is forbidden, development all the way to romance, whoa!
イジワルしちゃうぞしちゃうぞ
I'll tease you, I'll tease you!
惚れちゃいな
Fall for me!
ドキドキ肝心なドライ
A thrilling, crucial dry spell!
イジワルしちゃうぞしちゃうぞ
I'll tease you, I'll tease you!
可愛くね
Being cute?
付き合ってとかダメダメ独占じゃん
Saying "let's go out" is a no-no, isn't that monopolizing?
イタズラァニャ！イタズラァニャ！イタズラァニャ！怒らないでね
Mischief-nya! Mischief-nya! Mischief-nya! Don't get mad!
イタズラァニャ！イタズラァニャ！イタズラァニャ！アタシだけの愛
Mischief-nya! Mischief-nya! Mischief-nya! Only my love!
イタズラァニャ！イタズラァニャ！イタズラァニャ！怒らないでね
Mischief-nya! Mischief-nya! Mischief-nya! Don't get mad!
イタズラァニャ！イタズラァニャ！イタズラァニャ！アタシだけの愛寂しがりなさい
Mischief-nya! Mischief-nya! Only my love, be lonely!
近づいている 冬の足音 耳を澄ませば 聞こえる鈴の音…
Winter's footsteps are drawing near, if you listen closely, you can hear the sound of bells...
寝ぼけた頭に 響く目覚ましを 手さぐりで止めたあと 雪の気配
The alarm ringing in my sleepy head, stopped by feel, leaving a hint of snow.
寝ぼけた頭に 響く目覚ましを
The alarm ringing in my sleepy head,
手さぐりで止めたあと 雪の気配
stopped by feel, leaving a hint of snow.
始まりを告げる すてきな季節が
A wonderful season announcing the beginning is here!
Happy holidays, happy holidays, what a glorious time of year!
すやすやと眠る 子供達の手に
In the hands of children sleeping peacefully,
抱かれたテディベアも もう待ちきれない
the hugged teddy bear can't wait any longer either.
The teddy bear held in arms cannot wait any longer either.
クリスマスが今年もやって来る
Christmas is coming again this year,
悲しかった出来事を消し去るように
as if to wipe away all the sad things that happened.
さあ パジャマを脱いだら 出かけよう
Now, take off your pajamas and let's go out!
少しずつ白くなる 街路樹を駆け抜けて
Dashing through the street trees that slowly turn white.
華やぎ始めた 街は急ぎ足
The town that began to sparkle is in a hurry.
贈り物決まる頃 黄昏れてく
By the time gifts are decided, dusk falls.
かじかんだ指を ママが温めるね
Mom warms chilled fingers.
Happy holidays, happy holidays, What a glorious time of year!
大切なものは みんなそばにある
The important things are all close by.
穏やかな毎日が 続くぜいたく
Hoping peaceful days will continue luxuriously.
クリスマスがもうじきやって来る
Christmas is coming soon once again.
うれしさをかくせない 犬や猫まで
Even dogs and cats can't hide their joy.
もみの木に灯る 明かりをうけて
Bathed in the light shining on the fir tree,
いつもよりやさしそうな パパの目が笑ってる
Dad's eyes look kinder than usual, making me smile.
クリスマスは誰にもやって来る
Christmas comes to everyone.
もしひとりぼっちでも 淋しがらずに
Even if you're all alone, without feeling lonely,
心に住むサンタに呼びかけて
call out to the Santa living in your heart,
幼い頃の夢を 思い出してみごらんよ
and remember your childhood dreams.
クリスマスが今年もやって来る
Christmas is coming again this year,
悲しかった出来事を消し去るように
as if to wipe away all the sad things that happened.
さあ パジャマを脱いだら 出かけよう
Now, take off your pajamas and let's go out!
少しずつ白くなる 街路樹を駆け抜けて
Dashing through the street trees that slowly turn white.
Happy happy holidays, Happy happy holidays
Nightmare あなたは夢に 勝手に入り込んで
Nightmare, you sneak uninvited into my dreams,
気が狂いそうほど 夢中にさせて
making me so absorbed I feel like I'm going crazy.
消えてゆく Every Morning 芝生に寝転ぶ彼 まるで別人のなの
Fading away every morning, tossing on the lawn like a stranger.
挑発されたい 刺激的に 情熱的にね
I want to be challenged, excitingly, passionately.
In My Dream 赤い薔薇の花 部屋中にいっぱい敷き詰めて
In My Dream, spread red roses all over the room,
シルクのベッドで 愛し合おう朝まで
and make love on a silk bed until the morning.
I can't get enough your love
In My Dream 目覚めさせないで 邪魔はさせない 誰にも
In My Dream, don't let me wake up. I won't let anyone get in the way.
耳元でいつも エンドレステープのように ささやいていて
Whispering in my ear always like an endless tape,
Love me forever
Day Dream 何度誘っても
Day Dream, no matter how many times I invite you,
何度誘っても 話しても 上の空
No matter how many times I invite or talk to you, you're miles away.
分離したカフェ・オレは
Our café au lait separates
二人の心みたいに冷めてる
and cools down, just like our hearts.
期待とは裏腹に 後退する気分
Contrary to what I hoped, I feel myself pulling back.
触発されたい 野生的に 官能的にね
I want to be aroused, wildly and sensually.
In My Dream 空の彼方まで
In My Dream, way out into the sky,
エンジン全開で 走りながら
racing full throttle as we run,
永遠の愛を 語ろう朝まで
let's talk of eternal love until morning.
I can't get enough your love
In My Dream 飾らない涙で
In My Dream, with unadorned tears,
悲しみさえも 分かち合おう
let's share even our sadness.
何処にもないような 素晴らしい real love
A wonderful real love like nowhere else,
手に入れるまで I wanna sleep forever
until I make it mine, I wanna sleep forever.
In My Dream 赤い薔薇の花
In My Dream, red roses
部屋中にいっぱい 敷き詰めて
spread all across the room,
シルクのベッドで 愛し合おう朝まで
let's make love in a silk bed until morning.
I can't get enough your love
In My Dream 目覚めさせないで
In My Dream, don't let me wake up,
邪魔はさせない 誰にも
I won't let anyone get in our way.
耳元でいつも エンドレスステップのように 囁いていて
Always whispering in my ear like an endless step.
In My Dream 空の彼方まで
In My Dream, way out into the sky,
エンジン全開で 走りながら
racing full throttle as we run,
永遠の愛を 語ろう朝まで
let's talk of eternal love until morning.
I can't get enough your love
In My Dream 飾らない涙で
In My Dream, with unadorned tears,
悲しみさえも 分かち合おう
let's share even our sadness.
何処にもないような 素晴らしい real love
A wonderful real love like nowhere else,
手に入れるまで I wanna sleep forever
until I make it mine, I wanna sleep forever.
Starduster
[Title: Starduster]
誰より大切な君に
To you, more precious than anyone,
愛されないことを恐れて
fearing you wouldn't love me back,
一万年先の星まで
I fled all the way to a star
ひとっ跳びで逃げた
ten thousand years away in a single bound.
そっと瞼を開けてみる
Gently opening my eyelids,
目の前は黒い空の海
before me is a black sea of the sky.
一億年先の地平まで
All the way to the horizon a hundred million years away,
流れてゆくんだ
it flows away.
吸い込んだ
I inhaled...
真空の温度で
With the temperature of the vacuum,
感覚が凍りつく前にも
before my senses freeze over,
この身体一つの...
give me love for this single body of mine...
愛を
Love,
愛を 今すぐ
Love, right now,
愛を 私に
Love, to me,
愛を どうか
Love, please,
愛を 愛を 愛を
Love, love, love,
光りさす星の上で
Upon a star shining with light,
暗闇に飲まれないように
So as not to be swallowed by the darkness,
一万年先の夕焼けを
A sunset ten thousand years away
一人で見てた
I was looking at alone.
きっとこの宇宙の塵と ずっと漂うだけなんだろう
Surely drifting forever as dust in this universe.
そうやって消えてなくなる前にどうか
Before I vanish away like that, please,
どうか
Please...
愛を 今すぐ
Love, right now,
愛を 私に
Love, to me,
愛を どうか
Love, please,
愛を 愛を 愛を
Love, love, love,
親孝行って何？って考える
Wondering what filial piety even is,
でもそれを考えようとすることがもう親孝行なのかもしれない
Just trying to think about it might already be filial piety.
子供の頃たまに家族で外食
When I was a child, eating out with family occasionally,
いつも頼んでいたのはチキンライス
The thing I always ordered was chicken rice.
豪華なもの頼めば二度と連れてきてはもらえないような気がして
Feeling like if I ordered something luxurious, I'd never be taken out again,
親に気を使っていたあんな気持ち
That feeling of being considerate to my parents,
今の子供に理解できるかな？
Can today's children understand it?
今日はクリスマス 街はにぎやか お祭り騒ぎ
Today is Christmas, the town is bustling and festive.
七面鳥はやっぱり照れる
Turkey is still awkward after all.
俺はまだまだチキンライスでいいや
I'm still fine with chicken rice.
貧乏って何？って考える
Wondering what poverty even is,
へこんだとこ へこんだ分だけ笑いで
Filling the hollows with laughter to match the hollows,
昔話を語り出す時まで
Until the time comes to tell tales of old,
貧乏自慢ですかと いう顔をするやつ
People make that look like, "Is that your poverty brag?"
でもあれだけ貧乏だったんだ
But we really were that poor.
せめて自慢ぐらい させてくれ
At least let me brag about it a little.
最後は笑いに 変えるから
Because in the end, I'll turn it into laughter.
今の子供に 嫌がられるかな
I wonder if today's kids would hate it?
今日はクリスマス 街でにぎやか お祭り騒ぎ
Today is Christmas, the town is bustling with festive noise.
七面鳥は やっぱり照れる
Turkey is still a bit embarrassing,
俺はまだまだ チキンライスでいいや
I'm fine with just chicken rice.
今ならなんだって 注文できる
Now you can order whatever you want.
親の顔色を 気にしてチキンライス
Worrying about parents' faces, just ordering chicken rice.
頼むことなんて 今はしなくてもいい
You don't have to ask for anything like that now.
好きなものなんでも 頼めるさ
You can order whatever you like.
酸っぱい湯気が 立ち込める向こう 見えた笑顔が 今も忘れられない
Beyond the rising sour steam, the smile I saw is still unforgettable.
今日はクリスマス 街でにぎやか お祭り騒ぎ
Today is Christmas, the town is bustling with festive noise.
でかいケーキもってこい でもまあ全部 食べきれるサイズとな
Bring on a huge cake! But wait, in a size we can actually finish eating.
赤坂プリンス 押さえとけ スイートとまでは 言わないが
Book the Akasaka Prince, though I won't go as far as a suite.
七面鳥もってこい これが七面鳥か 思ったよりでかいな
Bring on the turkey! So this is a turkey? It's bigger than I thought.
やっぱり俺は チキンライスがいいや
Actually, I still prefer chicken rice.
よーし！あとは、ツリーをライトアップさせたら完成だー！
Alright! Next, if we light up the tree, it's complete!
ということで、あの第三、よろしくね、パワーだよ！
So, uh, Daizan, please do your best, give it some power!
第三！発電！いけー！
Daizan! Generate power! Go!
がんばれ走れ走れ！いけいけいけいけがんばれ！
Run hard, run, run! Go go go go, do your best!
がんばってるマジで！おっ、すごいすごい、発電できてる！
He's really trying! Oh, awesome, he's generating power!
いけいけ、もっともっと！こっちが、わー！だんだんね、ちょっと、ええあ、やれよやれよやれ、いけるよ！
Go go, even more! This way, wow! Gradually, uh, come on, you can do it!
第三大丈夫？こぼれ？第三？あれ？
Daizan, are you okay? Overflow? Daizan? Huh?
あ、疲れてる！第三、ほっぺたふくらませながら、息が、息が
Ah, he's tired! Daizan, puffing out his cheeks, his breath is...
あ、ぜぇぜぇしてる。え、ちょっと、でも、でも第三まだ、あらいきって言って、あー、どうしよう！
He's huffing and puffing. Eh, wait, but Daizan still has rough breathing, ah, what should I do!
でも、あのさ、それさ、のえちゃんがね、その箇所回したいところだけど、ちょっとのえちゃんの体重じゃあ、あの壊れちゃうんで
But you know, Noel wants to spin that part, but with Noel's weight, it'll break...
第三が頼みなんで、ツリー完成目指して走るんだ！がんばれ！いけいけ！がんばれ！
So Daizan is the one asked, run aiming for the tree's completion! Do your best! Go go! Do your best!
がんばれがんばれ！いけいけ！がんばれがんばれ！あーがんばってる、いいよいいよ！
Do your best! Go go! Do your best! Ah he's doing great, good job!
いけいけ！お、回ってる回ってる！お、待って待って！
Go go! Oh, it's spinning, it's spinning! Oh, wait, wait!
ツリー、あ、光りはじめてる！すごいよ！あ、いい、きてるきてる、光った光った！
The tree, ah, it's starting to light up! That's amazing! Ah, nice, it's coming, it lit up!
がんばれ！あともうちょっと！いけいけいけいけ！
Do your best! Just a little more! Go go go go!
あっ、あっ、待って、あとちょっと星が点滅すれば
Ah, ah, wait, just a little more if the stars light up,
もう成功なんだけど、あっ、きちゃった！
it'll be a success, ah, they're here!
わーい！
Yay!
星が光ったぞーい！
The stars are shining!
さんきゅー！ありがとっ！
Thank you! Thanks!
次、次、は、は、喜びのリアクション！
Next up is a reaction of joy!
ツリーのライトアップできましたー！やったー！
The tree lighting is done! Yay!
きょ、今日の作業だー！
T- Today's work is done!
はあ、本当にエモいだよお！
Ah, I'm really getting emotional!
いや、これクリスマスもう完璧なんじゃないのか？
Wait, isn't this Christmas already completely perfect?
ねえ、あれ？ちょっと待って
Hey, huh? Hold on a second.
もしや…雪が…あ！
Could it be... snow...? Ah!
やば、降ってる！なんか今ポチュって雪がね、降ってきましたね！
Oh no, it's snowing! It just started sprinkling snow!
喜びのリアクション！
A reaction of joy!
ホワイトクリスマスだ！最高だクリスマス！
It's a white Christmas! Christmas is the best!
ちょっと、祝っちゃいますか！
Shall we celebrate a bit?
祝うために、歌いますかっ！
To celebrate, shall we sing?
では、歌おー！
Then, let's sing!
わあ、雪だー！
Wow, it's snow!
不思議だね いまの気持ち
It's strange, the way I feel right now,
空から降ってきたみたい
feels like it came falling from the sky.
特別な季節の色が
The special colors of the season
ときめきを見せるよ
show their excitement.
初めて出会った時から
Since the first time we met,
予感に騒ぐ心のMelody
the melody of our hearts throbs with premonition.
とめられないとまらない な・ぜ
Unstoppable, won't stop, why?
届けて 切なさには
Deliver it, to this bittersweetness
名前をつけようか “Snow halation”
shall we give a name? “Snow halation”
想いが重なるまで 待てずに
Before our feelings can overlap, without waiting,
悔しいけど好きって純情 微熱の中
frustrating, but it's pure love called 'I like you', in a slight fever,
ためらってもダメだね
hesitating won't do any good.
飛び込む勇気に賛成 まもなくStart!!
Approve the courage to jump in, start soon!!
音もなく 気配もなく 静かに運命は変わる
Without sound, without a sign, fate quietly changes.
これからの未来に胸の 鼓動が早くなる
For the future ahead, the beating of our hearts grows faster.
例えば 困ったときには すぐ駆けつけて
For example, when you're in trouble, I'll rush right over
抱きしめたくて
and hold you tight.
どこにいても どこでも Fly high
No matter where you are, anywhere, fly high.
急いで いつの間にか 大きくなりすぎた “True emotion”
Hastily, before I knew it, true emotion grew too big.
夢だけみてるょじゃ 恋人は君って言いたい
If we're just dreaming, I want to say you're my lover.
優しい目が とまどってる イヤだよ
Your gentle eyes are hesitant, I hate that.
このまま 一気に愛情 あずけてPlease!
Leave it all to love right now, please!
届けて 切なさには
Deliver it, to this bittersweetness,
名前をつけようか “Snow halation”
shall we give a name? “Snow halation”.
想いが重なるまで 待てずに
Before our feelings overlap, without waiting,
悔しいけど好きって純情 微熱の中
frustrating, but it's pure love called 'I like you', in a slight fever.
ためらってもダメだね
Hesitating won't do any good.
不思議だね いまの気持ち
It's strange, the current feeling
空から降りてきたみたい
Seems like it came falling from the sky
飛び込む勇気に賛成
Approve the courage to jump in,
まもなくStart!!
the start is near!
いやあ、今日は本当に
Yeah, today is truly...
最高なクリスマスライブさーん！
the best Christmas Eve stream!
いや、あとは本物のサンタさんを来るのを待つのみ！
And next up, is waiting for...
と、
...the real Santa Claus!
その前にですね、
Before that, though...
ま、サンタさんはまだ来ないんですけど、
Well, Santa hasn't arrived yet, but...
なんと、スペシャルな方からメッセージが届いているらしいですよ！
surprisingly, a special message has arrived!
ええ、こちらのモニターをご覧ください。
Please take a look at this monitor.
団長！メリークリスマス！
Director! Merry Christmas!
メリークリスマス！
Merry Christmas!
皆さんこんにちは、雪花ラミィです。
Hello everyone, it's Lamy!
改めまして、こんな素敵なクリスマスライブに呼んでいただきありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for inviting me to such a wonderful Christmas stream.
今年もクリスマスがすごく好きで、オーツリーを飾ったり、ずっとクリスマスのBGMを聞いたりしています。
I love Christmas so much that I've been decorating a tree and listening to Christmas BGM.
いや、わかる！
I know, right?
ラミィちゃん見てほしい！今日、コスプレを用意してきました。
Lamy, I want you to see this—I prepared a cosplay for today!
毎日2章でノエルちゃんが着ていた、シスター×黒髪が本当にかわいくて、あとなんかここがショートカットになってるノエルちゃんもすごく新鮮で、もう心に刺さったので今回このためにコスプレを用意してきました。
Every single day in December, Noel-chan has been wearing this Sister outfit with short hair, and she looks so fresh and it really touched my heart, so I prepared this cosplay just for today!
ありがとうございます！嬉しい！
Thank you so much! I'm so happy!
今日は皆さんとノエルちゃん、クリスマスライブですっごく楽しんでると思うんですけど、
I'm sure everyone and Noel-chan are enjoying this Christmas stream to the fullest, but...
はい、もう一つ、
Wait, one more thing.
大事な日を忘れていませんか？
Did you forget an important day?
大事な日？
An important day?
それは、えみちゃん、あなたのお誕生日です！
It's your birthday, Lamy-chan!
ノエルちゃん、改めてお誕生日おめでとうございます！
Noel-chan, happy birthday once again!
あ、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
いつもノエルちゃんの可愛いエプロンしてる姿を見ているんですけど、
I always see Noel-chan wearing that cute apron,
やっぱりお誕生日はお祝いしたいなと思って駆けつけました。
but I really wanted to celebrate your birthday, so I rushed over!
いつもね、これからも活動を応援しております。
I'll continue to support your activities from now on too.
はい。
Yes!
以上、よりみゆでした！改めてノエルちゃんお誕生日おめでとう！バイバーイ！
That's all from Lamy! Once again, happy birthday, Noel-chan! Bye-bye!
いかないで、もゆちゃ、あっ、もゆちゃ、バイ、バイバーイ！
Wait, Lamy-chan, Lamy-chan, bye-bye!
もゆちゃ、バイ、バイバーイ！
Lamy-chan! Bye-bye!
もゆちゃ！
Lamy-chan!
か、可愛かった。
So cute!
もゆちゃん、あの団長のね、あのシスター衣装のコスプレをしてくれ、まさかの、
Lamy-chan actually wore that Sister outfit from Chapter 2 for me.
なんかまさかの、なんかサプライズみたいな感じだったんですけど、
It felt like some kind of surprise.
えっ、でも、なんかありがとうございますなですけど、
And I'm like, "Thank you so much," but...
クリスマス？お誕生日？
Christmas? My birthday?
あ、でも、おたん、お誕生日なら、
Oh, but if it's my birthday...
とりあえず、あ、あれがあるってことかな？
that means... there should be *that*?
ということで、え、今年もあります！
So, yes! This year too...
え、こちら、だだん。
Here it is, ta-da!
しのはねのえる、え、誕生日記念2024、わあ、出てきた！
Shirogane Noel's Birthday Celebration 2024 is out!
はい、詳細を見ていきましょう。まずは、
Let's check out the details! First is...
こちら！
this!
はい、え、ノエサンタがお届け！アクリルジオラマスタンド！
Noesanta's Delivery! Acrylic Diorama Stand.
ということで、あの、イラストレーターさんは、あのミョイさんに、あのこしらえていただきました。ありがとうございます！
The illustrator, MyungYi-san, drew this for us. Thank you so much!
これ、ね、可愛い、あのノエサンタですよね。
This is such a cute Noesanta, right?
たぶん団員さんにプレゼントをこもって行こうとしてるところなんじゃないかなって感じなんですけど、めちゃ可愛い！
She's probably heading out to deliver presents to the Dantsu!
いや、本物のサンタはもしかして、え、ノエちゃんだったのかなと思いつつ、いやこちらね、おうちにぜひぜひ飾ってみてください。
I was thinking the real Santa might actually be Noesanta, and you should definitely display this at home!
え、そして次は、こちら！
And next is this!
え、のえちゃんランダム缶バッチということでね、
Noe-chan Random Can Badges!
いっぱいいあるんですけれど、あの、団長ね、缶バッチってあんまりなんかっていうか、ま出したことないよね。
There are so many, but you know, I haven't really made many can badges before.
でもね、いろいろ憧れてたんです。あの、他のね、ホロメンとかがさ、こういう誕生日とか周年とかに缶バッチ出して、それを、あの団員さんとかね、あの、集めて、ね、くれると、あの、なんかこう、ずになっちゃん、ま、そのリスナーさんが集めてぴょんぴょんぴょんぴょんって
I've always admired other holomem releasing them for birthdays or anniversaries, and having Dantsu collect them...
あの、なんだ、イタバッグとか作ってんのをみて、団員さんもぜひノエちゃんのイタバッグとか作ってほしいなっていう。
Like making an ita-bag! So I want Dantsu to make a Noe-chan ita-bag too!
あの、団員さんはね、他の女の子の缶バッチ買っちゃだめだからね、ちょっと、言葉間違えちゃいました。
Though Dantsu shouldn't buy other girls' can badges, oops, I misspoke!
え、こちらはイラストレーターしかたない先生に描いていただきました。
These were drawn by Shika Tanaise-sensei!
いろいろね、衣装のノエちゃん、ぜひぜひ、あの単品でも売ってますので集めてください。
Noe-chan in various outfits are on sale individually, so please collect them!
どれが来てもね、嬉しいし、いっぱいちょっとかぶっちゃってもね、あの、イタバッグにすればオッケー！
Whichever ones you get, I'll be happy, and if you put them all in an ita-bag, perfect!
え、そして次はこちら！
And next is this!
はい、え、ノエサンタぬいぐるみキーホルダーということで、ノエサンタのぬいぐるみキーホルダーです。
Noesanta Plushie Keychain!
先ほどご紹介した、
As I introduced just earlier,
はい、アクリルジオラマスタンドの衣装と同じ、
yes, featuring the same outfit
え、ノエサンタとなっております！
as the acrylic diorama stand, the Noesanta version!
かわいいでしょ？こちらオリジナル衣装となっていますので、
Isn't it cute? This is an original outfit,
あの今日のね、記念というか、お祝い思い出だねに、
so please decorate it to commemorate today,
ぜひぜひ、あの飾ってください。よろしくおねがいします。
or as a memory of this celebration! Thank you.
ま、思い出といったら、こちらもちほしいよねということで、
Well, speaking of memories, you'd want this too, right?
次はこっち！
So next is this!
はい、団員さんとの思い出オーナメントキーホルダーということで、
Yes, the "Memories with Danchou Ornament Keychain"!
あのこちらですね、ま団長さんクリスマスツリーにぽぽぽぽぽぽぽんって、あのオーナメント飾ったと思うんですけど、
Danchou decorated her Christmas tree with ornaments going pop, pop, pop, pop...
こちら、あの、はい、えーとグッズにしちゃいました。
but we actually made it into merchandise.
しかも団員さんもね、あの一生懸命、あの回し車ね回してくれて、えー参加してくれてたので、はい。
And Danchou's members worked hard, running on the hamster wheel and participating, so yeah.
でも、団長ね、ちょっと忘れてたことが、こちら。
But Danchou, you know, there was something she forgot—this right here.
どん。
Ta-da.
あの、みんなに投げるのを忘れてました。
I forgot to throw them to everyone.
で、やっぱね、なんかネタがあったほうがいいかなということで、
So, to have some funny material,
思い出とついたら、やっぱ団員さんのもとに届けなきゃいけない。
when it comes to memories, we've got to deliver them to the members!
だから団長、ここでさ「わー」って投げるから、団員さんキャッチしてください。
So Danchou will yell "Waa!" and throw it, so please catch it!
ね、そのキャッチしたやつが、まあなんかちょっと思い出として、団員さんのキーホルダーとなって、これもしっかり付いてくるみたいな手で行きましょう！
Whatever you catch will become a Danchou member keychain, coming along with it!
手って言っちゃダメか。まあ行くよ！
No, can't say by hand. Well, here we go!
受け取ってね！えいやー！
Catch it! Eiyaaa!
あああ！叩いた！
Ahhh! I hit it!
やばい、なんかハムスターたちがこ、おれのんだ、おれのんだ、おれのんだってなんかすごいね、競争していたんですけど、
The hamsters were competing so hard, going "It's mine! It's mine! It's mine!"
あの、ごご購入いただければ、ごご購入いただければね、皆さんのもとに届くので、喧嘩しないでねっていうことで、
but if you purchase it, it'll reach everyone, so please don't fight!
え、次もあります。次はこちら！
So, next we have another one. Next is this!
はい。まあ、ノエちゃんと言えばASMRかなと思い、
Thinking ASMR suits Noe-chan,
え、ASMRボイス、ノエサンタからのお便りもちょっとこちら、はい、あのご用意させていただきました。
we've prepared an ASMR voice, "A Letter from Noesanta."
まあ、どんな内容なのかは、ま聞いてのお楽しみでございます。
Well, as for what kind of content it is, please look forward to it.
ぜひぜひ聞いてくれると嬉しいです。そして次はこちら！
I'd be so happy if you listen to it. And next is this!
はい、フルセット購入特典ということで、はい、今回もフルセット購入特典あります！
Yes, we have a full set purchase bonus this time too!
え、こちらはですね、ま数量限定と、あの、ま数量限定じゃないバージョンがあるんですけど、何が違うか、違うかと言うと、
There's a quantity-limited version and a regular version. What's the difference?
数量限定は直筆サインをかかせていただきます！
The quantity-limited one comes with a handwritten signature!
で、数量限定じゃない方は箱押し（箔押し）複製となっておりますので、ぜひ直筆、あの頑張って書くのでゲットしてみてください。よろしくお願いします。
The regular one features a foil-stamped reproduction, so please try to get one!
ま、団長、いやノエちゃん的には、まなんか、クリスマスね、ま一応今日クリスマス・イブちゅうことで、
Since today's Christmas Eve,
あの、まあ団員さんたちもね、自分の日頃の、ね、やっぱプレゼントとしてこのグッズ、あの、お手に取ってみてくれると嬉しいんじゃな…楽しい、ハッピーなんじゃないかなと。
wouldn't it be great if you could pick up these goods as a gift for your daily efforts?
いや、ノエちゃんも嬉しいって、よろしくお願いします。
Noe-chan is happy too, so thank you.
はい、そして改めて、フルセットはちらとなります。
And once again, here is the full set.
はい。ていうこと で、はい、いやすごいたくさん、なんか思い出セットみたいになっておりますので、ぜひ、あのクリスマスプレゼントにゲットしてみてください。団長も欲しいよ！
It's become like a huge memories set, so please get it as a Christmas present!
そして、え、プレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、今年の9月から発売された、ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードがなんと1枚付きます！
As a full set bonus, a Hololive Official Card Game card will be included!
いや、これ嬉しい！ノエちゃんも欲しい！
I'm so happy! Noe-chan wants one too!
いや、カードはホロライブプロダクション公式ショップでご購入された方のみ対象となります。
The cards are only available from the official Hololive Production shop.
特典につくのは、推しをアピールできるキーカード、「推しホロメンカード」です！
The bonus is the "Oshi Holomem Card" to show off your oshi!
カードの詳細や遊び方についてはホームページにてご確認ください。カードは日本語版のみとなります。
Please check the homepage for details. Cards are in Japanese only.
この配信の後にカートオープンです！
The cart opens right after this stream!
あの数量限定もあるので、ぜひ欲しいなって思ってる人はお早めにゲットしてみてください。
There's a quantity-limited version, so grab it early if you want one.
そして、この後22時20分からメン限があります！嬉しいね！
And right after this at 22:20, there's a member-only stream!
ちょっとね、まだまだ、あの、ノエちゃんと一緒にいたいなっていう団員さんいっぱいいると思うので、ぜひねメンバー登録をして待っててください。
Please register as a member and wait for it if you want to stay longer.
今回はですね、ま2曲歌おうかなと、思っております。
This time, I'm planning to sing about two songs.
そして、このね、あの、去年発表したこのね
And, you know, the one announced last year...
かわいい
Cute!
衣装もちょっとスクショタイムとかも
I've set aside some time for outfit screenshots
設けて、うんいっぱい撮ってもらうかなって思うので、ぜひよろしくお願いします！
and stuff, so I hope you take lots of them! Please look forward to it!
ということで、
So anyway...
今日はクリスマスなのかお誕生日なのか？
Is today Christmas, or is it my birthday?
なんかもう、なんかわけがわかんなくって、ちょっと意見もね、綺麗に出してしまって、
I'm getting so confused, my thoughts are all jumbled up,
え結局どっちなんだ？
Wait, which is it in the end?!
え待て、もう頭がわかんなくなって、うわっ！わかんなくなってきた！うわーー！どれっちだー！
Wait, my brain isn't working— Ah, I don't get it anymore! AHH! Which one is it?!
うーん、うわあ！誕生日、クリスマス！
Ugh... Whoa! Birthday? Christmas?!
あれ？さっきまで、待って、カレンダー... えっと、あ、2024年のあれ11月の...
Huh? Just a second ago... wait, the calendar... Um, oh, November 2024...
あれ？11月24日に丸がついて、あれハートになってる！
Huh? There's a circle on November 24th... Wait, it's a heart!
てことは、今日はクリスマスじゃないの？
Does that mean today isn't Christmas?
あれ？ってことは今までの全部、夢だったってこと？
Huh? So that means everything until now was a dream?
あ！そっか！今日はクリスマスイブの1か月前の誕生日なんだんだ！そう、よくね、あの...
Ah! Right! Today is my birthday, exactly one month before Christmas Eve! Yeah, you know...
クリスマスイブの1か月前が、だっちゃんの誕生日だよとか言ってるから、ごっちゃになってたのか！
people always say "Dat-chan's birthday is one month before Christmas Eve," so I got them mixed up!
うわあ、ちょっと...あのうっかりしてたな。まあでも、眠いからもう一回寝るか。
Whoa, I was... being so careless. Oh well, I'm sleepy, so I'll go back to sleep.
ま、ちょっと夢の中でまた生誕祭いいわおやすみー
Well, I'll celebrate my birthday in my dreams again. Goodnight!
今日はこのままさよならじゃないよ、
Today isn't a goodbye that ends right here.
手をとってくれたなら、
If you take my hand,
秘密も眠りにつくような夜に、君を連れていくよ。
I'll take you to a night where even secrets drift off to sleep.
それは例えば、遠く離れていたって、
That means, for example, even if we're far apart,
手を繋いできられるような奇跡のような話をしよう。
let's talk about a miraculous story where our hands remain connected.
窓は開けておいて。
Leave your window open.
今日までを思い出して、ひとつひとつ並べたら、
Remembering up until today, and lining them up one by one,
明日の雨が気になりだして、どうも眠れないみたいだ。
I start worrying about tomorrow's rain, and somehow I just can't sleep.
変わりたくないことや、変わらなきゃいけないことも、少し忘れたまま窓の外を眺めていたんだ。
With things I don't want to change, and things I have to change, slightly forgotten, I gazed out the window.
雨が降り出すその前に、君のところまで行けるような気がして、
Before the rain starts falling, feeling like I can go all the way to where you are,
目を閉じてみたんだ。そして、このまま遠くへと行こう！
I tried closing my eyes. And let's go far away just like this!
手をとってくれるかな。
Will you take my hand?
秘密も眠りにつくような夜を、君と泳いでいくよ。
I'll swim through a night where even secrets sleep, alongside you.
街の灯りが消える度に笑って、路地裏で抱き合おう。
Smiling every time the city lights fade out, let's embrace in the back alleys.
馬鹿みたいな話をしよう。
Let's talk about foolish things.
窓は開けておいて。聞こえる？
Leave your window open. Can you hear it?
聞こえる？
Can you hear it?
愛しいことや、なくせないものを教えてくれたのは今日みたいな、
What taught me precious things and irreplaceable things was a night just like today,
夜を重ねて織り上げてきた私たちに響く音。
a sound that resonates with us, woven together through accumulated nights.
夜が来るたびに心が踊ってしまうのは、
Every time night falls, my heart dances with excitement,
また一つ重なっていくから。目を閉じてみたんだ。
because another piece piles up. I tried closing my eyes.
今夜、私たちだけで眠ろう。誰にも言わないで。君が眠りにつくその少し前に。
Tonight, let's sleep just the two of us. Don't tell anyone. Just a little before you drift off to sleep.
名前を呼んで
Call out names...
叶わない願いに胸は痛んで
My chest aches with unfulfilled wishes,
俯いてしまうけど、
and though I hang my head,
誰もいない街へ誘いに行くから！
I'm going to invite you to a town where no one else is!
今日はこのままさよならじゃないよ。
Today doesn't have to be goodbye just yet.
手をとってくれたなら
If you'll take my hand,
秘密も眠りに就くような夜に君を連れていくよ。
I'll lead you into a night like secret sleep.
それは例えば、遠く離れていたって手をつないでいられるような奇跡のような
Even if we're far apart, like a miracle,
話をしよう。
let's talk.
窓は開けておいて聞こえる？
Keep your window open—can you hear it?
愛おしいことや無くせないものを教えてくれたのは今日みたいな
Today is like reliving precious things and irreplaceable moments.
夜を重ねて織り上げてきた私たちに響く音
Stacking up the nights, the sounds that echo within us...
響く言葉。
The words that resonate.